LOHITHA YALAVARTHI

abla

lohiyalavarthi95@gmail.com

- **** +18199192249
- **♦** 5 -121 4e avenue, Sherbrooke, Quebec, J1G 2L2
- **in** lohithayalavarthi
- Ω LohithaYalavarthi

A progressive thinker with excellent communication and decision-making skills possesses 5+ years of rich experience as a Full Stack Developer. Skilled in problemsolving and data structures and algorithms. Sound academic background, Recently graduated with a master's in Computer Science.

Portfolio:

https://portfolio1-gilt-eta.vercel.app/

Skills

DATABASE: MYSQL,SQL SERVER, POSTGRESQL, ORACLE,MONGODB, DYNAMODB

Education

Bishops University

Jan. 2021 to Sept. 2022

Course Work: Software Engineering, Database Theory, Machine Learning, Graph Theory, Data Mining, Deep Learning

Amrita University

Aug. 2012 to May 2016

Bachelors of Computer Science and Engineering 2016

Employment

CGI INC

Sherbrooke, Quebec, CA Iuly 2021 to Current

Technical Support Analyst

- Responsible for troubleshooting hardware and software issues and providing solutions.
- Using remote access, Service now, Active directory and Service desk Tool Kit, and a lot of other apps for troubleshooting issues.

CloudThing India Senior Software Engineer

India

Apr. 2019 to Jan. 2021

- Experienced in building Responsive Web and Mobile Applications using React, React Native, NextJs, TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and NodeJS.
- Experienced in creating REST APIs and communicating the requirements with clients, and Collaborated with designers to build design mockups to UI and delivered quality-driven applications.
- Experience with GIT to deploy in various environments (AWS) and integrate databases.
- Worked in an agile environment, engaged in the scrum, contributed to planning discussions, and delivered the project.

I-Exceed Technologies Solutions Pvt. Ltd Software Developer

India

Jan. 2016 to Apr. 2019

- Worked mainly on HTML, CSS, JavaScript/jQuery, React, NodeJS and integrated rest APIs.
- Handled, Designed & Implemented, and Tested web applications and Delivered the Application with the best Quality driven & with the best User Experience for Bank Users.

VERSION CONTROL : GIT,SVN, GITHUB

TECHNOLOGIES: REACT, PHP, JAVASCRIPT, ES6+, HTML, CSS, AWS, DOCKER

METHODOLOGIES: SDLC, AGILE.

DESIGN TOOLS: FIGMA

TOOLS: VISUAL STUDIO CODE, SUBLIME AND JIRA